# **IKEOLUWA ADETONA**

LEGAL PRACTITIONER, REAL ESTATE CONSULTANT AND AN ADVOCATE OF SUSTAINABLE DEVELOPMENT

**LinkedIn Profile:** <u>linkedin.com/in/ikeoluwa-adetona-983b20155</u> ikeoluwaadetona@gmail.com | +2348109474571 Associated Estates, Lifecamp Extension, FCT- Abuja



My Portfolio

### PERSONAL SUMMARY

I am a diligent lawyer with a distinctive capacity to learn new things and adapt to new areas of law. I have a keen interest and experience in sustainability, legal services, teaching, gender equality advocacy, management and consultations, conflict resolution, and entertainment law. I can identify problems, research and evaluate competition, and offer effective solutions to problems.

### ARTICLE

Ikeoluwa Adetona. (2023) Money Laundering (Prevention and Prohibition) Act, No. 14, Laws of the Federation, 2022 (MLPPA): A Step Towards Achieving a More Effective and Balanced Approach to Combating Money Laundering in Nigeria. *Section on Legal Practice Law Journal*, Vol. 9.

# **EXPERIENCE**

1. National Assembly of Nigeria - FCT- Abuja Legislative Aide, Policy Analyst on Marine and Environmental

Matters

June 2023 till Date

- Legal Review, Policy Analysis
- Legislative Drafting, Including but not limited to bills, motions and petitions
- 2. AA. MALAMI (SAN) & Co--- FCT- ABUJA---- Legal Associate August 2022- June 2023

The chamber of the minister of Justice and Attorney General of the Federation 2015-2023--

#### 2.1 DUTIES

- Researching and analyzing legal cases, statutes, regulations, and precedents.
- Preparing memos, contract reviews, and other legal documents and providing litigation support.
- Conducting interviews with witnesses, experts, and clients.

### 2.3 KEY ACHIEVEMENTS

- Developed and implemented detailed statements of strategy, new case strategies, and plans for several high-profile legal cases, resulting in successful outcomes for clients.
- Successfully managed complex legal cases for top corporations, delivering exceptional results and maintaining strong relationships with clients.

### 3.--- 9 BILLION HOMES LTD---

# **Project Manager, Legal and Real Estate Consultant**

September 2021 - March 2022

- ---This was a 6-month project. I was contracted to help the company start off. My roles included;
- Providing legal advice on safe investments and recommendations for Sustainable Community Development to the company.
- Maintaining detailed records and reports of site inspections, client inquiries, visits, and feedback using.
- Additionally, I assisted marketers by teaching them the application of property law to their daily marketing activities.

# 4. EXCELLENT SQUARE INVESTMENT NIGERIA LTD, FCT-ABUJA FCT-ABUJA -- Sole Legal Consultant June 2020 - July 2021

- Ensuring appropriate documentations for contracts and sales of land and properties.
- Giving legal advise and safe investment and Sustainable Community Development recommendations to Clients and Marketers, whilst assisting Marketers by teaching them
- the application of property law to their daily marketing activities.
- Ensuring that the rights of the Staff and the Managements are protected in every disputes according to the Nigerian Constitution and requisite statutes.

# 5. A1 MEGA MANAGEMENT AND CONSULTANCY Fct- Abuja. November 2019 to May 2020

- Maintenance of detailed administrative reports, recording and reporting all adverse findings to legal staff.
- Delivering professional drafts to clients on real estate matters, specifically; Tenancy Agreements Deed of Assignment ---- Power of Attorney---
  - Contractual Agreements Company incorporation

### **4.1 KEY ACHIEVEMENTS**

- Completed the first project with the company- Excellent Mega City, Behind River Park, Lugbe by preparing all the contractual agreements, Deed of Assignment and Power of Attorney.
- Introduced investors and buyers to the company and ensured that the rights of the Staff and the Management are protected in every disputes according to the Nigerian Constitution and requisite statutes.

# **EXTERNSHIP & INTERNSHIP**

- ALUKO AND OYEBODE LAW FIRM, Maitama, FCT-Abuja (May 2019 to July 2019)
- SENIOR MAGISTRATE COURT WUSE ZONE 2 (May 2016 to June 2016)
- TOKUNBO ORIMOBI LLP, Lagos (May 2016 to June 2016)

# **ACADEMIC QUALIFICATIONS**

- Nigerian Law School, FCT-Abuja --- November 2018 to November 2019--- B.L: Bachelor of Laws
- University of Lagos, Nigeria -- January 2014 to October 2018 ---- LLB: Bachelor of Laws Department of Law (Second Class Upper Honors - GPA of 3.73)
- University of Lagos, Nigeria: School of Foundation Studies : Session: 2013/2014 UNDER The Joint Universities Preliminary Examinations Board (JUPEB) European Studies. ---- Scored 15/16 Points

**CERTIFICATES** 

- Certificate of Recognition International Conference on Law & Religion, Brigham Young University, 2015.
- Certificate of National Service, 4th November,
- Certificate of Attendance NBA-ICLE 62nd **Annual General Conference, Nigeria**

**SKILLS** 

- Detailed and effective legal contract drafting.
- Digital technology and Graphic Designs Knowledge and Skills.
- High level of competence in the use of the Microsoft Office.
- Research and advocacy skills.
- Strong event planning, supervisory and management skills
- Strategic- relationship and partnership building skills
- Effective listening and spoken English communication skills.

**AWARDS** 1. BEST Graduating Student at Saint Louis Grammar School. Mokola, Ibadan: Year 2013 2. BEST Graduating Prefect at Saint Louis Boarding House, Mokola, Ibadan: Year 2013

# **MEMBERSHIP BODIES**

- Institute of Charteted Mediatiors and Conciliations of Nigeria(ICMC)
- Nigerian Bar Association
- NGO: Welfare Secretary: Federation of Oyo State Unilag Chapter 2015/16

### REFERENCES

Olalekan Ashas, LL.M **Director of Practice, Litigation** Matrix Solicitors, LLP T: +234 8023374200 E:lekanashas@matrixsolicitors.com

O.A.K Osinnowo

**Senior Associate** Tokunbo Orimobi LP T: +234 80261334703 E: oakosinnowoa@gmail.com. Dr Akinola Akintayo Senior Lecturer and Legal Consultant **University of Lagos** T: +234 805 203 6007 E: akinat2002@yahoo.com